{"tossups": [{"question": "<b><u>This man argued that the \"Cherokee Nation [was] a foreign nation in the sense</u></b> <b><u>of our Constitution and law\" in</u> </b><em><b><u>Cherokee Nation v. Georgia</u></b></em><b><u>. This man, with Daniel</u></b> <b><u>Webster, argued for the defense in the U.S. Supreme Court interstate commerce case</u></b> <b><u>(+)</u></b> <em><b>Gibbons v. Ogden</b></em><b>. Along with running mate Amos Ellmaker, this man was the presidential nominee for the Anti-Masonic Party in 1832. The prosecuting attorney in (*) </b>Aaron Burr's treason case, for the points, who was this longest-serving U.S. attorney general?", "answer": "William <b><u>Wirt</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This test was first published to the scientific community in 1836. A namesake</u></b> <b><u>chemist first developed this test after being called by the prosecution, leading to the</u></b> <b><u>acquittal of John Bodle. This test\u2019s first practical application occurred in 1840 in</u></b> <b><u>France after a wife was accused of (+)</u> poisoning her husband, Charles. After Mathieu Orfila used this test to detect a poison in her husband\u2019s bloodstream, Marie (*)</b> Lafarge was sentenced to life imprisonment. For the points, name this highly sensitive test used in forensic toxicology to detect arsenic.", "answer": "<b><u>Marsh</u></b> test", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This headline was the most notorious product of a newsroom culture which</u></b> <b><u>awarded a tin hat to Tom Petrie, who was addressed as \"Commander\" for the</u></b> <b><u>duration of a conflict. Headlines preceding this one from the same paper's coverage</u></b> <b><u>included \"WE'LL SMASH EM\" and \"STICK IT UP YOUR (+)</u> JUNTA\" [[HOON-tah]]. Rupert Murdoch personally overruled editor Kelvin MacKenzie's suggestion to substitute \"DID 1200 (*)</b> ARGIES DIE?\" instead of, for the points, what one-word May 1982 headline used by <em>The Sun</em> to report on the sinking of the <em>General Belgrano</em> [[hay-nay-RAHL bail-GRAH-noh]] during the Falklands War?", "answer": "\"<b><u>GOTCHA</u></b>\"", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Later joined by William Lewis and Richard Peters, this man was the first judge</u></b> <b><u>on the court for the District of Pennsylvania. This signatory of the Declaration of</u></b> <b><u>Independence was a member of the Continental (+)</u> Marine Committee, which introduced a resolution that led him to provide a (*)</b> design for only \"\"a Quarter Cask of the public Wine.\" For the points, identify this Founding Father known for the arrangement of stars and stripes in his early designs for the American flag.", "answer": "Francis <b><u>Hopkinson</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This emperor called off an attack on Chen after hearing that its Emperor Xuan</u></b> <b><u>was said to have died. This emperor replaced a system established by Cheng Qun</u></b> <b><u>[[CHUN]] in Cao Wei that gave (+)</u> government officials one of nine-ranks with a procedure that would come to rely on the eight-legged essay. The imperial civil service exam was instituted by this emperor, who led a campaign against the Goguryeo. He oversaw a project that aimed to improve the efficiency of (*)</b> grain transportation throughout China. For the points, the Grand Canal was constructed by what ruler of the Sui Dynasty?", "answer": "Emperor <b><u>Wen</u></b> of Sui (accept <b><u>Yang Jian</u></b>; accept <b><u>Puliuru Jian</u></b>; accept <b><u>Narayana</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man's \"inborn disposition\" was blamed for his actions in a satirical</u></b> <b><u>\"defense\" by Mark Twain. This commander oversaw a victory at Calumpit, after which</u></b> <b><u>he was tasked with organizing the capture of the self-proclaimed president under the</u></b> <b><u>Malolos Constitution. This general (+)</u> worked with the Macabebe [[mah-kah-BEH-beh]] Scouts to infiltrate a camp in Palanan. A general who became the symbolic target of the anti-imperialist (*) </b>movement, for the points, who is this man who took Emilio Aguinaldo prisoner during the U.S. pacification of the Philippines?", "answer": "Frederick \"Fighting Fred\" <b><u>Funston</u></b> (accept \"A Defence of General <b><u>Funston</u></b>\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Two days after the technology was presented to this president, Saint-Malo</u></b> <b><u>became the site of the Minitel service, a forerunner to the Internet. A 30-year period</u></b> <b><u>of economic growth known as (+)</u> Les Trente Glorieuses came to an end under the presidency of this man, who worked with Helmut Schmidt to help establish the European Monetary System. This man received nearly 51% of the vote in one election against the Socialist candidate, (*) </b>Fran\u00e7ois Mitterrand. For the points, name this French president from 1974 to 1981.", "answer": "Val\u00e9ry <b><u>Giscard</u></b> d'Estaing (or Val\u00e9ry Ren\u00e9 Marie Georges <b><u>Giscard</u></b> d'Estaing ; prompt on \"VGE\"; prompt on \u201cd\u2019Estaing\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This event\u2019s planners adopted the name Righteous Army and adopted an</u></b> <b><u>earlier event\u2019s slogan with the password \u201cRevere the Emperor, Destroy the Traitors.\u201d</u></b> <b><u>This event was perpetrated by the Young Officers of the (+)</u> Imperial Way Faction. This event resulted in the assassination of several of Hirohito\u2019s ministers in an attempt to weaken the military\u2019s political power. This event was modeled as a \u201c20th-century (*) </b>Meiji Restoration.\u201d For the points, name this failed 1936 coup where a group of Japanese soldiers tried to restore direct rule by the Showa Emperor.", "answer": "<b><u>2-26</u></b> Incident (or <b><u>February 26</u></b> Incident; or <b><u>Ni Ni-Roku Jiken</u></b>; prompt on descriptions)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>One man with this name is the namesake of a trio of ivory triptychs, including</u></b> <b><u>individual examples named for Charles Borradaile and Julius Wernher. John</u></b> <b><u>Kourkouas was appointed to lead an eastern campaign waged by the first emperor of</u></b> <b><u>this name who, though not Basil, waged a war with Bulgaria. The title</u> (+) Lekapenos was given to a ruler of this name, another of whom was served by Andronikos Doukas. The fourth ruler of this name was defeated by (*)</b> Alp Arslan in 1071. For the points, give this name of various Byzantine rulers, the fourth of whom lost at Manzikert.", "answer": "<b><u>Romanos</u></b> (accept <b><u>Romanus</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this war, Autaritus allegedly cut off the hands of men under Gisco and</u></b> <b><u>buried them alive in pits. Mathos was killed during an attack on the port city of Leptis</u></b> <b><u>Parva during this conflict, in which (+)</u> Spendius participated. This conflict arose due to wage disputes among African soldiers and those of a certain island. A massacre in Sardinia occurred during this (*) </b>\u201cTruceless War\u201d that saw tens of thousands of soldiers mutiny in Sicily. Concluding with the Battle of the Saw, for the points, name this bloody mutiny fought in the wake of the First Punic War.", "answer": "<b><u>Mercenary</u></b> War (accept <b><u>Truceless</u></b> War before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>An 1890 Broadway adaptation of</u> </b><em><b><u>L'\u00e9toile</u></b></em><b><u> with this title starred Francis Wilson.</u></b> <b><u>An annual festival of this name held in Hilo honors a man who oversaw the</u></b> <b><u>restoration of the hula and other cultural traditions.</u> (+) Kal\u0101kaua of Hawai'i was often referred to by this epithet, which was also used to describe a Restoration-era king who, though married to (*)</b> Henrietta Maria, fathered numerous illegitimate children with mistresses. For the points, name this epithet held by Charles the Second of England.", "answer": "The <b><u>Merry Monarch</u></b> (accept The <b><u>Merrie Monarch</u></b> Festival; prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In 1944, Faustino Espinoza Navarro oversaw the historical reconstruction of a</u></b> <b><u>festival dedicated to this deity. According to legend, this deity, whose name is derived</u></b> <b><u>from the Puquina language, once ordered a capital city to be built where a (+)</u> golden wedge entered the Earth. Mart\u00edn de Mur\u00faa depicted a brother of Huayana Yupanqui worshipping this deity at Coricancha. The origin of the widespread practice of worshipping this deity is sometimes attributed to (*)</b> Pachacuti. Various statues of this supposed son of Viracocha were found throughout the main temple of Cusco. For the points, name this Incan sun god.", "answer": "<b><u>Inti</u></b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "<b><u>Reverend Eleazar Thomas was among the casualties of this conflict, during</u></b> <b><u>which a man known as the \"Curly-Headed Doctor\" was a leader. In this conflict,</u></b> <b><u>fighting occurred at a stronghold in what is currently Lava Beds National Monument.</u></b> <b><u>The Battle of (+)</u> Lost River occurred during this conflict, in which Edward Canby was killed by a group including its leader Kintpuash. Involving a group that departed from the Klamath Reservation, (*)</b> for the points, what was this 1870s conflict named for a Native American people inhabiting Oregon and California?", "answer": "<b><u>Modoc</u></b> War (accept <b><u>Modoc</u></b> Campaign; accept <b><u>Lava Beds</u></b> War before \u201cLava Beds is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Every four years this battle is commemorated with the August 7 proclamation</u></b> <b><u>of one country's president at the Palacio de Nari\u00f1o. Taking place roughly two weeks</u></b> <b><u>after the Battle of Vargas Swamp, this battle led to the flight of</u> (+) viceroy Juan de Samano. Jos\u00e9 Barreiro led the losing Royalist forces at this battle at which Francisco de Santander assisted the victor in bringing about the end of the New Kingdom of (*) </b>Granada. Occurring roughly 100 miles from Bogota, for the points, what was this major victory for Simon Bolivar in what is now Colombia?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Boyac\u00e1</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>One ruler of this dynasty overstruck coins of the Western Satrap king</u></b> <b><u>Nahapana with portraits of himself. That ruler of this dynasty also oversaw</u></b> <b><u>restoration efforts at the Sanchi stupa in modern-day (+)</u> Madhya Pradesh. According to the Puranas, this dynasty defeated the Kanvas in 28 BC, and this dynasty was once ruled by Vasishthiputra Pulumavi before its end in the (*)</b> 200s AD. Amaravati was among the capitals of, for the points, what dynasty of the Deccan that was once ruled by Gautamiputra Satakarni?", "answer": "<b><u>Satavahana</u></b> Dynasty (accept <b><u>S\u0101dav\u0101hana</u></b> Dynasty; accept <b><u>Andhra</u></b>s)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The first Republican Party presidential platform attacked this document\u2019s</u></b> <b><u>\u201chighwayman\u2019s plea, that \u2018might makes right.\u2019\u201d Pierre Soul\u00e9 was the primary architect</u></b> <b><u>of this document, which one administration (+)</u> reluctantly made public. A cartoon from the Election of 1856 depicts James Buchanan being mugged by miscreants quoting this document. The right of the U.S. to conquer (*)</b> Cuba was asserted by, for the points, what document named after the Belgian city where its signatories met?", "answer": "<b><u>Ostend Manifesto</u></b> (accept <b><u>Ostend Circular</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This film popularized an association of its central character with the quote</u></b> <b><u>\"Whoever will come to us with a sword, from a sword will perish.\u201d Hermann Balk,</u></b> <b><u>who held the non-chess title of Grand Master, appears in this film, in which Gavrilo</u></b> <b><u>vies for the hand of Olga. Sergei (+)</u> Prokofiev wrote the score for this 1938 film, which begins with the conquest of Pskov and features an engagement centered around (*)</b> Lake Peipus. The Battle on the Ice is depicted in this film directed by Sergei Eisenstein. For the points, name this film focusing on a Prince of Novgorod.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Alexander Nevsky</u></b></em> (do not accept or prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {"question": "<b><u>Traditions surrounding this ruler parallel those of Ogier the Dane and</u></b> <b><u>Constantine the Eleventh.</u><u>After this non-Frenchman\u2019s death in 1578, his subjects</u></b> <b><u>remembered him as \"the desired\" or \"the sleeping.\" Though presumed to have (+)</u></b> <b>died in battle, this king's body was never found, leading to hopes of his imminent return. This king was one of the \"three kings\" who died at the Battle of Alc\u00e1cer Quibir [[al-SAH-sehr kih-BEER]]. (*)</b> Succeeded briefly by cardinal great-uncle Henry, for the points, name this king whose death at 24 eventually led to Spanish control of Portugal.", "answer": "<b><u>Sebastian</u></b> of Portugal", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man\u2019s son succeeded him in the United States Senate in 1965. This man\u2019s</u></b> <b><u>political machine, according to John Gunther in a 1947 edition of</u> </b><em><b><u>Inside U.S.A.</u></b></em><b><u>, was</u></b> <b><u>\u201cthe most urbane and genteel dictatorship in America.\u201d During the presidential</u></b> <b><u>election of 1960, this</u> (+) Virginian received fifteen electoral votes, eight in Mississippi, six in Alabama, and one in Oklahoma, and the America First Party and Constitution Party nominated this man for vice president in 1952 on a ticket headed by Douglas MacArthur. This man spearheaded (*)</b> Massive Resistance to racial desegregation. For the points, name this longtime senator from Virginia.", "answer": "<b><u>H</u></b>arry F(lood) <b><u>Byrd, Sr.</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A judge refused to convict a mob of the murder of Francis McIntosh and</u></b> <b><u>believed this person influenced the victim\u2019s decision to fatally stab a policeman. The</u></b> <b><u>father of John Brown compared this man\u2019s death to the beheading of John the Baptist.</u></b> <b><u>This man\u2019s death took place during a (+)</u> riot at a warehouse owned by Winthrop Sergeant Gilman, a site at which he was hiding his fourth printing press. Considered by some to be the \u201cfirst casualty of the (*) </b>Civil War,\u201d for the points, what abolitionist died while defending his anti-slavery newspaper <em>The St. Louis Observer</em>?", "answer": "Elijah Parish <b><u>Lovejoy</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this period, a group with a name meaning \u201cContinuous Struggle\u201d</u></b> <b><u>targeted the National Agricultural Bank. A \u201cBlack Prince\u201d helped plan an attempted</u></b> <b><u>coup during this decades-long period. A series of strikes demanded pay raises during</u></b> <b><u>the (+)</u> Hot Autumn of this period. For 55 days of this period, one leader was held in captivity and later killed by the Red Brigades. Aldo (*)</b> Moro was kidnapped during this period, in which a train station in Bologna was bombed. For the points, name this turbulent 20th century era of Italian history.", "answer": "<b><u>Years of Lead</u></b> (accept <b><u>Anni di piombo</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The namesake figure in this work is \"settled after a variety of fortunes, near</u></b> <b><u>the banks of the river Delaware.\" A similar work by J. Hector St. John de Cr\u00e8vec\u0153ur</u></b> <b><u>may have been inspired by this piece, which was written in response to the</u> (+) Townshend Acts. An American figure comparable to Cincinnatus is the central figure in this work, whose author would draft the (*)</b> Olive Branch Petition. For the points, name this series of essays by John Dickinson that took a pastoral writing style to advocate against British taxation.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Letters from a Farmer in Pennsylvania</u></b>, to the inhabitants of the British Colonies</em> (accept <em><b><u>Letters from a Pennsylvania Farmer</u></b></em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Grover Norquist managed this man's campaign as national president of the</u></b> <b><u>College Republicans, after which he spent a decade working in film production,</u></b> <b><u>including producing and writing the Angolan Civil War drama</u> </b><em><b><u>Red Scorpion</u></b></em><b><u>. While</u></b> <b><u>working for the government of the Northern Mariana (+)</u> Islands, this man successfully lobbied Congress for exemptions from labor laws. This man's downfall came when his activities on behalf of seven different tribal groups ensnared congressman Robert Ney (*) </b>and other politicians. Exposed by Earl Devaney, for the points, name this American lobbyist whose gross overbilling of his Indian reservation clients led to a bribery scandal in 2006.", "answer": "Jack (Allan) <b><u>Abramoff</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Diodorus claims the winning commander of this battle was able to cross one</u></b> <b><u>feature unopposed because the defending forces were told not to move for the rest of</u></b> <b><u>the day. The winning commander of this battle enslaved 2,000 mercenaries for</u></b> <b><u>fighting against (+)</u> fellow Greeks. This battle\u2019s winning commander was saved from Sphithridates by (*) </b>Cleitus the Black, ensuring victory over Darius the Third. For the points, name this first of three major victories against the Persian Empire by Alexander the Great, fought near a namesake river.", "answer": "The Battle of the <b><u>Granicus</u></b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Of this man, William Wilberforce once said he knew no equal in terms of</u></b> <b><u>\"personal purity, disinterestedness and love of this country.\" Only Robert Walpole</u></b> <b><u>served a (+)</u> longer tenure as prime minister than this man, who was the first to serve in the position following the passage of the Acts of Union of Great Britain and Ireland. In power during the (*)</b> War of the First Coalition, this man used Britain's economic might to expand the Royal Navy in his conflicts with Napoleon. For the points, name this British prime minister who had a father of the same name.", "answer": "William <b><u>Pitt the Younger</u></b> (prompt on \"William Pitt\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man, who was convicted of crimes against humanity in 1946, responded</u></b> <b><u>to his sentencing by saying, \u201cDeath by hanging... well, in view of the whole situation, I</u></b> <b><u>never expected anything different.\u201d This man served in the Third Reich as deputy</u></b> <b><u>governor in the General Government of occupied (+)</u> Poland and as commissioner for the occupied Netherlands. Responsible for the deportation of (*)</b> Dutch Jews, this is, for the points, what man who served for two days prior to the <em>Anschluss</em> [[AHN-shloos]] as chancellor of Austria?", "answer": "Arthur <b><u>Seyss-Inquart</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>First published in January 1908, this work was written by a British officer who</u></b> <b><u>established a site at Brownsea Island for the central individuals. That man who</u></b> <b><u>founded the organization that relied on this book had successfully defended Mafeking</u></b> <b><u>during a siege in the Second (+)</u> Boer War. Sections on tracking, mountaineering and pathfinding can be found in this work, which was written prior to the (*) </b><em>The Wolf</em> <em>Cub's Handbook</em>. Written by Robert Baden-Powell, for the points, what is this manual aimed at teaching outdoor skills to members of a youth organization?", "answer": "<b><u>Scouting for Boys</u></b>: A handbook for instruction in good citizenship (accept <b><u>Boy</u></b> <b><u>Scout</u></b> (or Scouts)<b><u> handbook</u></b> or similar answers)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A St. Alban\u2019s Abbey tomb allegedly containing this man's remains claimed he</u></b> <b><u>was \u201crich in nothing but in memory.\" This man\u2019s description of the Castle</u></b> <b><u>Sparrowhawk is thought to have been derived from Hetoum. The physician (+)</u> Jehan de Bourgogne [[bor-GOHN]] compiled the writings of this man. Cormorants described by Odoric are represented as \u201clittle beasts\u201d in one of a number of appropriations that this man has been accused of. His experiences in (*)</b> Egypt and Asia are chronicled in a work compared to one by Marco Polo. For the points, name this supposed French knight who published a book about his travels outside of Europe.", "answer": "Sir John de <b><u>Mandeville</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man, who was appointed U.S. deputy secretary of defense in 1963, served</u></b> <b><u>on the Knapp Commission that analyzed police corruption in New York City following</u></b> <b><u>the accusations of former officer (+)</u> Frank Serpico. As secretary of state, this man played a key role in the signing of the (*) </b>Camp David Accords between Egypt and Israel in 1978. For the points, name this U.S. secretary of state who resigned in opposition to Operation Eagle Claw, a failed rescue attempt of American hostages in Iran.", "answer": "Cyrus <b><u>Vance</u></b> (or Cyrus Roberts <b><u>Vance</u></b>, Sr.)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The GAO investigated claims of a rivalry involving Eric Wickson and Randy</u></b> <b><u>May in the aftermath of this event. This event occurred at 07:36 local time after a</u></b> <b><u>departure from another country's Incirlik base. Taking place during Operation</u> (+) Provide Comfort, this event resulted in 26 total deaths. This event came about from the misidentification of two vehicles as \"Hinds\" and bore similarities to an incident involving a (*)</b> Sikorsky craft during the Battle of Mogadishu the year prior. For the points, name this 1994 friendly fire incident in Somalia that resulted in two American helicopters being shot down.", "answer": "1994 <b><u>Black Hawk</u></b> shootdown incident (<b><u>Black Hawk Incident</u></b>; accept <b><u>Black</u></b> <b><u>Hawk Down</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In a piece for the</u> </b><em><b><u>National Anti-Slavery Standard</u></b></em><b><u>, this person described</u></b> <b><u>educating former slaves as a way of unlearning internalized White supremacy. As</u></b> <b><u>part of a revenge scheme, an attempt was made to sell this woman\u2019s two children (+)</u></b> <b>to different states but were instead bought by their father, Samuel Tredwell Sawyer. This person escaped the sexual harassment of James Norcom by (*)</b> hiding in a tiny crawl space above her grandmother\u2019s home for seven years. For the points, name this American escaped slave who wrote <em>Incidents in the Life of a Slave Girl</em>.", "answer": "Harriet <b><u>Jacobs</u></b> (accept Linda <b><u>Brent</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Along with a work depicting St. Francis, one of this man\u2019s paintings of the</u></b> <b><u>Virgin and Child was robbed from the San Francesco in Pisa by Napoleon\u2019s forces. In</u></b> <b><u>the</u> </b><em><b><u>Commedia</u></b></em><b><u>, Dante notes how this artist \u201cheld the field\u201d until he was</u> (+) eclipsed by a pupil. An unusually large amount of space in the center gives a three-dimensional quality to the </b><em><b>Santa Trinita Maesta</b></em><b> of this painter, whose best-known student created a series of frescoes for the (*)</b> Arena Chapel. Often considered the greatest painter of the 13th century, for the points, who is this Italian painter who taught Giotto di Bondone?", "answer": "<b><u>Cimabue</u></b> [[CHEE-mah-BOO-eh]] (accept <b><u>Cenni di Pepi</u></b>; accept <b><u>Cenni di Pepo</u></b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>One woman of this surname used the penname Esther Wyndham and wrote</u></b> <b><u>notable biographies of John Ruskin and a figure central to Theosophy, Jiddu</u></b> <b><u>Krishnamurti. Aside from Mary, a man of this surname designed a Stone of</u></b> <b><u>Remembrance in memory of those who died during World War One, as well as a</u></b> <b><u>palace for (+)</u> Osman Ali Khan, the final </b><em><b>nizam</b></em><b> of Hyderabad. That man may be better known for a memorial found on the Rajpath called the India Gate. That (*)</b> Englishman of this surname designed many landmarks in New Delhi. For the points, give this surname of the architect Edwin.", "answer": "<b><u>Lutyens</u></b> (accept Edwin Landseer <b><u>Lutyens</u></b>; accept Edith Penelope Mary <b><u>Lutyens</u></b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>This class received a total of 18 votes of the 193 in the Centuriate Assembly.</u></b> <b><u>Due to being exclusively available for senior officer positions, this class was replaced</u></b> <b><u>in the military units with which they were most strongly associated. This</u> (+) property-based class ranked just under the senatorial class in Roman society, and (*) </b>bronze statues of members of this class include a famous depiction of Marcus Aurelius. For the points, name this Roman class that was associated with the cavalry.", "answer": "<b><u>Equestrian</u></b> Order (accept <b><u>Equites</u></b>; accept <b><u>Eques</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In a cartoon titled \u201cThe Modern Gilpins,\" a man asks a member of this faction</u></b> <b><u>to stop and then informs them of the location of a house. Samuel Beardsley was a</u></b> <b><u>member of this faction, which split into the \"Hards\" and the \"Softs.\" A group opposed</u></b> <b><u>to this faction derived its name from a practice used to end (+)</u> rat infestations. William Marcy was a member of this group, which evolved out of the Albany Regency. (*)</b> Free Soilers were opposed by members of this Democratic faction which did not oppose slavery, unlike its rival. For the points, name this New York political faction which often clashed with the Barnburners.", "answer": "<b><u>Hunker</u></b>s (prompt on \"Democrats\" or \"Democratic Party\" before mentioned; prompt on \"Anti-Abolitionist\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Edward Luckhoo served as the last Governor-General of this country, where</u></b> <b><u>Arthur Chung served as its first president. Forbes Burnham led this country's</u></b> <b><u>transition to a republic, though his regime rigged elections until the eventual rise to</u></b> <b><u>power of (+)</u> Cheddi and Janet Jagan. This Caribbean country, whose \"six peoples\" include Indian settlers, was merged from the colonies of Berbice and (*)</b> Demerara-Essequibo. For the points, name this country that was conquered from the Dutch by the British, unlike neighboring Suriname.", "answer": "Co-operative Republic of <b><u>Guyana</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>At an event in this city, one man\u2019s speech was said to have \u201crang out across the</u></b> <b><u>meadow like a celestial organ\u201d. That sermon in this city was commissioned by Eugene</u></b> <b><u>the third and was delivered in support of the Second Crusade by Bernard of</u></b> <b><u>Clairvaux. From this location, one party decided to take a</u> (+) sea route from Marseille while another proceeded through the Alps by land. That 1190 meeting in this location involved the armies of (*) </b>Philip Augustus and Richard I. For the points, name this French city in Yonne where participants in the Third Crusade departed from.", "answer": "<b><u>V\u00e9zelay</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In 1949, Georgia O\u2019Keeffe donated 101 works of art to this university from the</u></b> <b><u>collection of her late husband, Alfred Stieglitz. As students of this university, Diane</u></b> <b><u>Nash and John Lewis organized successful sit-ins that integrated this university\u2019s</u></b> <b><u>city\u2019s downtown lunch counters. A 1909 recording of (+)</u> \u201cSwing Low, Sweet Chariot\u201d by a group associated with this university was added to the U.S. National Recording Registry. This university is named for Clinton, a general of the Freedmen\u2019s Bureau, and has a STEM-focused bridge program with nearby (*)</b> Vanderbilt. For the points, name this historically Black university in Nashville, alma mater of W. E. B. Du Bois and Ida B. Wells and famous for its Jubilee Singers.", "answer": "<b><u>Fisk</u></b> University", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}